(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T21:06:13.102219",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ああ、他人事みたいな夜だ
Ah, it's a night that feels like someone else's business.
ばら撒いた星だけがキラリ澄んでいる
Only the scattered stars are clear and sparkling.
そんなに綺麗にはなれないや それでも今夜、往くための歌
I can't be that beautiful, yet tonight, this is a song to keep going.
ああ、ほんの小さな夜だ
Ah, it's such a tiny little night.
寝るには早く、夜明けはまだ遠く
Too early to sleep, dawn is still far away,
憧れるには遠く、挫けるにはまだ早いや
Too far to yearn for, too soon to give up.
言葉はいつだって下手くそだよ
Words are always so clumsy,
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only my sighs get better.
傷付く度、違う生き物と知るよ
Every time I get hurt, I realize I'm a different creature.
いつだって闇で迷子
Always a lost child in the darkness.
明けない夜があったなら
If there was a night that never broke,
このまま溶けて消えたいや
I'd want to melt and disappear just like this.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there's a night that never breaks,
私は
I...
煌めく星になれなくて良い
Don't need to become a glittering star.
I don't need to become a glittering star.
ああ、本日は閉店です
Ah, we are closed for today.
どうにかこうにか一日
Somehow or other, I got through the day,
ひっそりこっそり良く頑張り
Working quietly and secretly hard,
何かは残せたのでしょうか?
Did I leave anything behind?
希望的だ 刹那的だ
It's hopeful, it's ephemeral,
楽観的だ でも
It's optimistic, but even so,
きっと美しいよ
It's surely beautiful.
言葉はいつだって下手くそだよ
Words are always so clumsy,
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only my sighs get better.
傷付いて、違う生き物と知って
Getting hurt and knowing I'm a different creature,
それでも精一杯歌うよ
Still, I'll sing with all my might.
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there was a night I wanted to cry,
笑えない夜があったなら
If there was a night I couldn't smile,
溶けて消えてなくなって
Melting and disappearing away,
きっと
Surely...
もう一度ゼロから始めよう
Let's start over from zero once more.
明日のことはわからないや
I don't know anything about tomorrow.
昨日のことも知らないや
I don't know anything about yesterday either.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there's a night that never breaks,
私は
I...
煌めく星になれなくて良い
Don't need to become a glittering star.
I don't need to become a glittering star.
会いたい想いが 相対な君の手で
My thoughts of wanting to see you in your opposing hand
跳ねて気まぐれ雑音
bounding with whimsical noise.
繋ぎたい感情論 試し合い感情論
A sentimental argument of wanting to connect, a testing sentimental argument
すぐに不安になるわ
that quickly turns into anxiety.
まァいいか しょうがないな
I guess I'm alright, there's nothing that can be done,
このまま消えてしまいたいな
I wish I could just disappear like this.
ここに いない いない いないのは 自分 自分
The one who isn't, isn't, isn't here... is me, myself.
誰も見ない 見ない 見ないままで 投げ捨てて さようなら
Unseen, unseen, unseen by anyone, casting it all aside and saying goodbye.
苦しくない 悲しくもない 透明な気持ち
Not painful, not even sad, a transparent feeling.
足りない自分 合わせ顔もない
My lacking self has no face to match with yours.
いない いない いないままで ここにいたい
Not being here, not being here, I want to stay here,
いたい いたい 笑いたいじゃない
want to hurt, want to hurt—isn't it that I want to laugh?
せーのっ
Ready, set!
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's no good,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
look, it won't work anymore.
心は進化するよ もっと もっと
Our hearts will keep evolving, more and more.
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If words will ruin our relationship,
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた 忘れてた だけど あれ? なんか違うかも
I thought we could just erase words... I forgot. But wait, is something off?
千里の道も 一歩から
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step,
石のように硬い そんな石で
with a resolve as hard as stone.
塵も積もれば大和撫でしこ 逝きぬきで いや死ぬ気で!
Dust piled up makes a Yamato Nadeshiko! With all my might—no, with the will to die!
ふわふわり ふわふわル
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
just you calling my name makes me float into the sky.
ふわふわル ふわふわり
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
just you smiling makes me smile too.
神様 ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも 巡り逢えたことが幸せなの
for even in fate's caprice, I'm blessed to have met you.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's no good,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
look, it won't work anymore.
心は進化するよ もっと もっと
Our hearts will keep evolving, more and more.
そう そんなんじゃ やだ ねえ そんなんじゃ まだ
Yeah, I don't want that. Hey, that's still not enough.
私のこと見ていてね ずっと ずっと
Keep on looking at me, forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど あなたの中の私の存在は まだまだ大きくないこともわかってるけれど
I know that my existence in you isn't as big as you in me,
今この同じ瞬間 共有している実感
but I feel the reality that we share this very moment.
塵も積もれば大和撫でしこ 約して散る時も大和撫でしこ
Dust piled up makes a Yamato Nadeshiko, promising even in fading to be a Yamato Nadeshiko!
くらくりり くらくル
Swooningly, swoonity,
あなたを見上げたら それだけで眩しすぎて
when I look up at you, just that is too dazzling.
くらくル くらくりり
Swoonity, swooningly,
あなたを想っている それだけで溶けてしまう
just thinking of you makes me melt away.
神様 ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも 巡り逢えたことが幸せなの
for even in fate's caprice, I'm blessed to have met you.
恋する 季節は 欲張り サキュレーション
The season of love is a greedy circulation!
恋する 気持ちは 欲張り サキュレーション
The feeling of love is a greedy circulation!
恋する 瞳は 欲張り サキュレーション
The eyes in love are a greedy circulation!
恋する 乙女は 欲張り サキュレーション
The maiden in love is a greedy circulation!
ふわふわり ふわふわル
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
just you calling my name makes me float into the sky.
ふわふわル ふわふわり
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
just you smiling makes me smile too.
神様 ありがとう
Thank you, God,
運命のいたずらでも 巡り逢えたことが幸せなの
for even in fate's caprice, I'm blessed to have met you.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ
Yup, I don't want it like that.
ねえそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's not enough.
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
I just want you to look at me forever and ever.
いやー、ライブ最高！
Man, this live is amazing!
ねぇ Noelさん何してた？
Hey Noel, what were you doing?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
どうしても伝えたくて
I really wanted to tell you...
よっしゃ
Alright!
あ、ありがと、ありがと！
Ah, thanks, thanks!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
そうなんよ
That's right,
1600歳になっちまったよ
I've turned 1600 years old.
あれ？でも1600歳では
Huh? But at 1600 years old...
え？永遠の1600歳ってこと？
Eh? You mean you're eternally 1600?
いやもっとそれ以上 もうそれ以下も歳取らないから
Well, more than that... or rather, you don't age past that.
なるほど
I see.
うん。永久的な存在
Yeah. An eternal existence.
ノエル！誕生日だから お願いがあるんだけど！
Noel! It's my birthday, so I have a favor to ask!
どうしたの？
What is it?
お願いって え、聞いてくれる？
A favor... Um, will you listen?
なに？
What?
えと、あの、一言だけ言っとくけど、え、大要求は上げられないからね
Um, I'll just say this, I can't grant big demands, okay?
うるさいよ！
Hey, shut up!
いらないこと言わなくていいの！いいの！
You don't need to say unnecessary things! It's fine!
え、ちょっちょっちょっ、ちょっとさ、お願い事なんだけどさ、ママになってほしいんだけど
Um, wait a second, I have a favor to ask... I want you to be my mama.
ママ？
Mama?
あれ、どうしたの？
Huh, what's wrong?
えちょっと、あの、最近さ、ほら、去年とかさ、ちょっといっぱいお仕事あってさ、ちょ、ちょこれちょっとさ、膝枕とかしてくれて
Um, recently, you know, like last year, I had a lot of work, and... um, you gave me a lap pillow...
わかったじゃあ、団長の膝においで
Got it. Then come to the danchou's lap.
やった！やったやった！え、いいのいいの？
Yay! Yay, yay! Eh, really, really?
いいよ
Sure.
じゃ、お邪魔します
Then excuse me.
あ、かわいいね
Ah, so cute.
ね、ママ！ねよっぴ、ずる！頑張ってて偉いね！
Hey, mama! Hey Neyoppi, you're sneaky! You worked hard, you're amazing!
ありがとう！あ、癒やされる…！もっとナデナデして！
Thank you! Ah, I'm healed...! Pat me more!
よしよしよし、よしよし、うれちゅ、うれちゅう！
There, there, there, so happy, so happy!
やべ！みんな見てた！
Oh no! Everyone was watching!
やば、今日ライブだったか
Oh crap, was this live today?
今日さ、あの、今日のことは忘れてください
Today, um, please forget about today.
すみません
I'm sorry.
え、あなたさ、せっかくだからさ、記念撮影しない？
Um, since you're here, how about we take a commemorative photo?
あ、そうなんだ。みんな見てるんですね
Ah, is that so? Everyone's watching.
そうそうそうそう。え、ちょっと一緒にさ、お写真撮ろう？
Yeah, yeah. Hey, let's take a photo together?
何を撮るんだい？
What are we taking?
こうやってこう、ちょっと近づいて、ぎゅっ！あ、そうだね、さっきの終わりのポーズ
Like this, getting a bit closer, hug! Ah, right, the ending pose from earlier.
ちょっと上からカメラさん撮れますか？
Can the camera person take it from above?
上からとか、ここから。ちっちゃくてかわいいの
From above, or from here. Small and cute.
ちょ、胸邪魔じゃない？
Hey, aren't your boobs in the way?
いや、邪魔じゃないよ。あたってないでしょ
No, they're not in the way. They're not touching.
ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、危ないよ
Wait, wait, wait, wait, it's dangerous.
じゃ、次さ、ちょっと、そこ、ちょっと
Then next, um, right there...
ブリッコしない
Don't act cutesy.
ブリッコ？あ、いいね、恋愛サーキュレーション歌ったし、かわいさアピールしとくか
Cutesy? Ah, nice, since we sang Renai Circulation, let's appeal our cuteness.
ちょっとブリッコしよ、ブリッコ。どう？ブリブリ
Let's act cutesy, cutesy. How's this? Fluffy fluff
どう？かわいい？いっぱくとって、かわいく
How's this? Cute? Take a lot, make it cute.
ウィンクとかしちゃおっかな
Shall I do a wink?
ウィンク
Wink.
で、最後にさ、あの、後ろにさ、バックのイラストがあったの分かる？覚えてる？
And finally, you know, there was a background illustration behind us, remember?
分かる、覚えてる覚えてる。ほんと？
I know, I remember remember. Really?
え、それでさ、ちょっと、あのそのポーズしたいんだけど
Um, so, I want to do that pose.
いいねいいね
Nice, nice.
いい？撮れるかな、スタジオの、方々
Good? Can we take it, studio staff?
あ、出た！これこれ！これさ、ノリをママがね、ちょ描いてくれてね
Ah, it appeared! This, this! This one, Norio-mama drew it for us...
めっちゃうまっ！
So good!
そうなの！どう？これちょ、このポーズしよう。かわいいでしょ。ほら！フリー素材です。後で手のひら抜いてかぶせてあげてください
That's right! How's this? Let's do this pose. Isn't it cute? Look! It's free stock material. Please remove the palms later and overlay them.
いっぱい撮ってね。撮ってね。え、もっとさ、こうさ、アップとかできますか？カメラさん
Take lots. Take them. Eh, can you zoom in more like this, camera-san?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
おお！かわいい
Ooh! Cute.
メイドさん、メイドさん！ねえメイドさんなんだよね
Maid-san, Maid-san! Hey, you're a maid, right?
ちょっとさ、メイドさん満足しちゃったから、もうこのまま…
Since Maid-san is already satisfied, let's just stay like this...
ノエルのママの膝の上でね
On Noel's mama's lap...
おねんねする？ちょっと休む、休憩します
Go to sleep? Rest a bit, take a break.
よしよし、いっぱい休んで
There, there, rest a lot.
よしよし、ノエルママ、よしよしよしよしして
Good, good, Noel mama, pat me, pat me
おやすみだよ、いっぱい寝てね
Time for bed, sleep tight.
おやすみ… おやすみ…
Good night... Good night...
灰色に濁んだ
Ash-white and murky,
言葉はカプチーノみたいな色してる
words are the color of cappuccino.
言い訳はいいよ 窓辺に置いてきて
Excuses are fine, leave them by the window,
数えきれないよ
I can't even count them.
灰色に濁んだ
Ash-white and murky,
心はカプチーノみたいな色してる
my heart is the color of cappuccino.
弄ろうカプチーノ 戯けた振舞いして
Let's play with a cappuccino, acting foolish.
さァ揺蕩うように雨流れ
Now, letting the rain flow like swaying waves,
僕らに荒す花に溺れ
drowning in the flowers devastating us,
君が褪せないような思い出を
praying for memories where you'll never fade,
どうか どうか どうか
please, please, please,
君が溢れないように
so that you won't overflow.
波待つ海岸
The shore waiting for waves,
紅い夕さす日
the red sun casting twilight,
窓に反射して
reflecting in the window.
八月のヴィスビー 潮騒
Visby in August, the roar of the sea,
街路樹の待ちぼうけ
waiting in vain by the roadside trees,
海風ひとつで
with just a single sea breeze.
夏を泳いだ 花の白さ 宵の雨
The white flowers we swam through in summer, the evening rain
流る夜に 溺れ
drowning in the flowing night,
誰も褪せないような 花ひとつ
a single flower so no one fades away,
どうか どうか どうか
please, please, please,
胸の内側に挿して
graft it inside my heart.
ずっとおかしいんだ 生き方ひとつ教えてほしいだけ
Something's been wrong for a while, I just want you to teach me how to live.
償えるものなんて僕にはないけど
Though I have nothing left to atone with,
何も答えられないなら 言葉ひとつでもいいよ
if you can't answer anything, even a single word is fine.
わからないよ 本当にわかんないんだよ
I don't know, I really don't know.
さァ揺蕩うように雨流れ
Now, letting the rain flow like swaying waves,
僕らに荒す花に溺れ
drowning in the flowers devastating us,
君が褪せないように書く歌を
writing this song so you never fade,
どうか どうか どうか
please, please, please,
今も忘れないように
so I won't forget even now.
またひとつ謎が分かって
Another mystery solved,
花ひとつを胸に抱いて
clutching a single flower to my chest,
流るまぶたの裏で 君が褪せないようにこの歌を
beneath my eyelids, singing this song so you never fade,
どうか どうか どうか 君が溢れないように
please, please, please, so you won't overflow.
ワー！ わー！ ありがとうー！
Yay! Yay! Thank you!
雨とカプチーノでしたー！
That was "Rain and Cappuccino"!
いや、本当難しかったー！
Man, that was really hard!
夜府たんのよろしくさ、めちゃくちゃいいね
Yofutan's "yoroshiku", it's super good!
いや、るしあのがさ、やっぱあってなって思ったんだよね。
I really thought Rushia's choice was so fitting.
いやいや、あのさ、その提案してくれたのってふうたんなんだよね。
No, no, wait, Fuutan was the one who proposed it.
そう、最初はね、るしかしさん絶対るしあと一緒に歌いたいと思ってたから、歌えてよかったー！
Right, at first, I really wanted to sing with Rushiacchan no matter what, so I'm so glad we could sing together!
いや、本当に入りがね、るしあが流しゅかさん好きなのわかってくれてて、うん。
Seriously, thank you. You knew that Rushia loved Rushiacchan, yeah.
でね、ふうたんも好きなんだよね、たしか。
And you also like Fuutan, right?
そう！でもね、今回初めて歌ったんで、あのルシアが、結局選んでくれたじゃない？
Yeah! But since we sang for the first time this time, well, Rushia ended up choosing it, right?
そうなの。私がるしかしさん歌いたいと思ってて、色々ね、こう候補とかも出したし、るしあからも出してくれてて、結局この選んだ曲、結果的に選んだこのアメとカプチーノ。
That's right. I wanted to sing with Rushiacchan, and put out various candidates, and Rushia did too, and in the end, this song we chose, 'Ame to Cappuccino'.
それをさ、るしあがさ決めてくれたのって結局、なん何がきっかけだったの？
And what ended up being the trigger for Rushia deciding on it?
あのね、すっごく迷ったの。迷ったんだけど、なんか、このアメとカプチーノってすごく切ないじゃん。
You know... I hesitated so much. I hesitated, but like, 'Ame to Cappuccino' is so bittersweet, right?
なんて言うのかな、心がシュンてなるような、なんか、でも暖かくなるような、なんて言うのかな。
How should I put it, something that makes your heart sink a bit, but also warms it up... how to say it?
すごい難しいんだけど、それの中でふうたんと歌いたいなってこう、もうインスピレーションで思ったの。
It's super difficult, but amidst all that, I just had this inspiration that I wanted to sing it with Fuutan.
ああ、絶対似合うなって思ったんだよね。ええ、うれしい！
Ah, I thought it would suit us so well. Oh, I'm so happy!
そう、なんか、お互いね、やっぱさ、合うのがいいじゃん。
Yeah, like, after all, it's good when it suits us both.
なんか、あんまり泣かなくてさ、こう、そうそう、なんかそのエモさみたいなのも入れたくてね、選んじゃ...まじめな話しゃちゃった。
And not crying too much, like, yeah, I wanted to put in that emotional vibe too, so I chose... oops, I got all serious.
いつもはね、「うわー！」って言ってるのに！
Usually you're like 'Waaah!', but!
今日はなんか、お洒落で可愛いじゃん。
Today it's kind of fashionable and cute, right?
ちょっと！ちょっとテレちゃうじゃん、ふうたん！えー！いいんだよ！って言っても！嫌だよ！
Wait! You're making me shy, Fuutan! Eh! It's fine! Even if you say that! No way!
今日はアイドルだからね、誕生日だし！
Today we're idols, after all, it's my birthday!
そうだよ。じゃあさ、なんかアイドルっぽいさ、なんか撮影とか一緒にすっえ？しようしよう！せっかくだからしよう！ええ、じゃあちょっと、ポーズポーズしようポーズ。
That's right. So, like, shall we do something idol-like, like taking photos together? Eh, let's do it! Since we have the chance, let's do it! Eh, then let's do a pose.
よしよしよしよし。え、ど、どうしようかないどうしようかな。あ、いいね、ここ、ここ。
Alright, alright. Eh, wh-, what should we do? Ah, nice, right here, here.
こうしようか。うん、こうこうこう。これして、アイドルだね。あ、ちょっと、とっ、みんな撮って撮って！撮ってください！上からとか、横からとか。
Let's do this. Yeah, like this. Do this, we're idols. Ah, wait, ta-, everyone take pictures! Please take them! From above, from the side.
あ、いいね。難しいよ、ハート。いけるかな？こう腰に、腰に、腰にこう、こう、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと。
Ah, nice. Heart is hard. Can we do it? Like this, on the waist, like this, wait, wait, wait.
あ、あ、あ、すごい、できる！できて、できてね！できた、できた！いいよ！可愛い、可愛い！可愛い！できてる！
Ah, amazing, we can do it! We did it! It worked! Great! Cute, cute! Cute, it worked!
どう、どう？あー、今日ね、めっちゃ歌いたかったふうたんと、やったね！ふう、ちょっと休んじゃおう？
How is it? Ah, today, with Fuutan who I really wanted to sing with, we did it! Fuu, shall we take a little break?
休む、休む。まだ歌えないんでしょ？だってみんなだって。
Rest, rest. You can't sing yet, right? Because everyone's like that.
もう、歌って終わらないんでしょ？
We're not done just with singing, right?
まだ、まだ。あ、ついてくんの？
Not yet, not yet. Ah, you're following me?
次のステージに連れてってくれるから、行くよ！がんばろう！おー！わーわーわー！
You're taking me to the next stage, so let's go! Let's do our best! Yay!
脳科学的にどうなの？
What do the neurosciences say?
解き明かしてよ ファーストインプレッション
Unravel my first impression.
この気持ちを抑えられないの
I can't hold back this feeling.
君のことが好きだということ以外は
Other than the fact that I'm in love with you,
脳科学的にどうなの？
What do the neurosciences say?
教えてくれよダーリン
Won't you tell me, darling?
解き明かしてよ ファーストインプレッション
Unravel my first impression.
君のことが好きだということ以外は
Other than the fact that I'm in love with you,
脳科学的にどうなの？
What do the neurosciences say?
教えてくれよダーリン
Won't you tell me, darling?
あぁ、るしあ、おめでとう！
Ah, Rushia, congratulations!
チューリングラブ！
Turing Love!
どうだった？
How was it?
いやぁ、楽しかったですね！
It was so much fun!
なんか二人でこんなイチャイチャと踊ったりとかなんかしちゃって
Doing all this hyped-up dancing together like this...
楽しかったね！
It was so fun!
イチャイチャしちゃったね。
We were all hyped up!
したね！
Yeah!
ねぇ、ねぇ！
楽しかったわ！いつもね、別の曲だったけど
It was so fun! I usually sing different kinds of songs,
初めて歌ったからね、
but since it was my first time singing this,
ねぇ！
Right?
新鮮だった！
It felt so fresh!
ねぇ、でも踊りもね、
Right? And the choreography...
めちゃめちゃ可愛くて大変で、
It was super cute and super hard,
もう楽しかった、思い出になった、思い出に！
but it was so fun!
思い出になった！
It became a great memory!
ダンス頑張ったね！
Dance worked really hard!
ねぇ、頑張った、頑張った！
Right? We worked so hard!
ねぇ、きれきれ！
Right? We sparkled!
ねぇ！
Right?
そう。
Yeah.
ねぇ、ねぇ、ねぇ！
Hey... hey, hey!
なんですか？
What is it?
なぁ、なんか寒くない？
Don't you think it's cold?
えっ？
Huh?
何急に？
What do you mean, "suddenly"?
なんかさ、
Well, you know...
はい、はい？
Yeah, yeah?
なんかもっと暖かくしてよ！
You should warm me up more!
えっ、暖かく？
What, warm you up?
じゃあちょっと抱き、抱きしめ合っちゃおうかな？って！
Then let's hug, let's hug each other!
おっ！
What?
おお、おいおいおい！
Oh, oh, oh!
おい、それめちゃ近い！近い、さっき！さっき！
That's close! That's close, wait, wait, wait!
もう、だ、近いよ！
That's close, you know!
あれ、あれ、さっき！あれ、さっきは！
Wait, wait, wait! Just now, wait!
さっきは近付いてばっかじゃん！
We got too close just now!
えっ？何が近付いたって、いいでしょ！
What? We didn't get close enough!
暖かいでしょ！
It was warm, wasn't it?
何が嫌なんだよ、言って見ろ！
Why are you acting all shy? Come on, let me try!
「離れてよ！」ちょ、待って！「離れ...」
"Get away from me!" Come on!
あ、でも、まり、まり、まり。
Ah, but wait, wait, wait.
でもさ、今のいいよね。ちょっと今のさ、ちょっとさ、みんな写真撮ってもらおう？
Let's have everyone take a photo!
あ、確かに！ちょっと撮ってもらおうじゃんか。
Ah, true! Let's have them take one.
今撮ってたじゃん。
Take one right now, yeah!
はーい、皆さん！どうですか？
Everyone, how is it?
ちょっと撮ってください！
Please take a photo!
どうですか？
How is it?
るし、離れて！超の、超の！
Rushia, step back!
はい、もう回り、おしまい！おしまい！
Alright, that's enough, time to wrap it up! Time to wrap it up!
もう、なんか続かないな。
Man, you're not cooperating.
おしまい。
We're done!
え,まだもう1ポーズくらい撮ってもらえますか？
Can we take one more pose?
あ、なんか取る？取る？
Can we take one? Can we?
やっぱちょっと「チューリングラブ」さ、ほら踊ったからさ、
Hey, since we danced "Turing Love"...
ちょっと「チューリングラブ」のポーズしますか？
Can we do the "Turing Love" pose?
あ、いいね！
Oh, nice!
よし、よし、よし。チューリング、これこれ、これ！
Let's do it, let's do it!
よいしょ！おい！
Here we go, hey!
チューリング、どうですか？
Turing... How is it?
はい、可愛いでしょう！撮ってね。
らぁ！
Take this!
チェックのキャミソールを着て
Wearing a checkered camisole,
今夜…ねぇ！遊びにゆくわ
tonight... hey! I'm coming to play!
スウィートな服は宝物
Sweet clothes are my treasure,
君は少し恥ずかしそうね
and you look a little shy.
ハートのネイルのピンクは…
The pink of my heart-shaped nails...
ホントはちょっと、大胆よ
is actually a bit bold!
12時すぎのシンデレラ
A Cinderella past midnight,
もっと夢見せて
show me more dreams,
もっとそばに来て
come closer to me,
tonight 二人きり
just the two of us tonight,
let's party!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛い子に生まれたかった
Born to be the cutest girl in the world!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回言われてもまだ不安だわ
No matter how many times you say it, I'm still uneasy!
あ・い・し・て・る？
Do you... lo-ve me?
カートにあふれてしまうほど
Overflowing from the cart,
今日は…ねぇ！お買い物の日
today... hey! It's shopping day,
スウィートな帽子と手袋
a sweet hat and gloves,
お洒落するとキラキラするの
dressing up makes me sparkle!
大きなハートが欲しい
I want a big heart,
ホントはちょっと弱虫よ
though I'm actually a bit of a coward.
シープのブーツ脱ぎ捨てて
Kicking off my sheep boots,
もっと愛される sweet girl
a sweet girl who is loved even more—
女の子 ねぇ 目指したい
Ah, a girl wants to aim for that!
from my heart
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛いって今日も言ってね
Tell me again today that I'm the cutest in the world!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回生まれても君に会いたい
No matter how many times I'm born, I want to meet you!
本当よ
It's true!
ハートのネイルのピンクは…
The pink of my heart-shaped nails...
ホントはもっと抱きしめてよ
Actually, hold me even tighter!
12時すぎのシンデレラ
A Cinderella past midnight,
もっと夢見せて
show me more dreams,
もっとそばに来て
come closer to me,
tonight 二人きり
just the two of us tonight,
let's party!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛いって今日も言ってね
Tell me again today that I'm the cutest in the world!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回生まれても君に会いたい
No matter how many times I'm born, I want to meet you!
約束よ
It's a promise!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一可愛いって今日も言ってね
Tell me again today that I'm the cutest in the world!
happy! fancy baby doll!
love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回生まれても君に会いたい
No matter how many times I'm born, I want to meet you!
ほら、踊り出そうよ
Hey, let's start dancing!
このさ、すぐ隣で見たらもう一緒でよくない？
If we look right next to each other, isn't it basically the same?
いやもうこんな
No, like, this
ファンシー美少女も、はい、まさにアイドルって感じじゃ、ねえ、やっぱぺこらだよな？
fancy bishoujo is, yes, totally giving off that idol vibe, right, isn't it Pekora after all?
でしょ、ターンとか可愛いかったりするじゃん、るしあたちの
Right? Like doing cute turns, you know, like Rushia and the others—
パーって回るやつ
doing that "whoosh" spinning thing!
これだよね、ね？
This is it, right? Right?
そうなんだよね。
That's right.
でね、ねえ、いくら、なになにぺこ？
And you know, hey, how much—wait, what is it, Peko?
るしあたちさ、芸人とか言われるじゃん。
People call Rushia and the others comedians, you know.
まあね、言われることが多いぺこですがね、で、まあアイドルじゃん。
Well yeah, I get called that a lot, Peko, but, well, we're idols, right?
そうぺこだね、だからこそさ、ちょっと今からさ、
That's right, Peko. That's precisely why, starting right now,
あの、可愛いポーズ対決しない？
um, shouldn't we have a cute pose showdown?
突然に、突然可愛いポーズと対決な？そう、アイドルらしいじゃん。
Out of nowhere? Out of nowhere, a cute pose showdown? That's right, it's very idol-like.
あ、じゃあ、どっちがなんか、あの、アイドルの力が強いかっていうのを、今、あれなの、決めるってことぺこ？
Ah, then, to decide whose idol power is stronger, like, we're deciding that right now, Peko?
今対決するとかと？
Like having a showdown right now?
うん、お腹ってきなさいぺこです、可愛いアイドル
Yeah, come at me, Peko! A cute idol—
あ、アイドルペコですからの任せなさい、どんなポーズでもできまっぺこですから。
Ah, an idol Peko, so leave it to me, I can do any pose, Peko!
一緒にやるの？一斉のせで二人でやるの？それとも片方ずつ見せていく感じ？
Are we doing it together? Doing it on the count of three? Or showing them one by one?
そうだね、一緒にやっぱりみんなにも写真とか撮ってほしいから、一緒にパッてやってみよっか。
That's right, together! We want everyone to take pictures, so let's do it together on "three."
ああ、オッケーぺこ、うん。
Ah, okay Peko, yeah.
え、待って、どうしようどうしよう、まず1個目どれにしようかな。
Eh, wait, what should we do? What should we do? First of all, what should the first one be?
ああ、可愛い、可愛いポーズ。うん、あれにしよう、ペコらが決めました。
Ah, cute, cute pose. Yeah, let's go with that one, Pekora decided!
はや、決まったの？
So fast, you've decided?
だから決まった、オッケーオッケー、決まった。行くよ。
That's why it's decided. Okay, okay, it's decided. Here we go.
じゃあジャッジの方もよろしく。オッケー、オッケー。
And judge, please take care of it too. Okay, okay.
せーの、はい！
Ready, set, go!
あれ、みんな一緒じゃね？
Huh, aren't we all doing the same thing?
え、ちょっと待って、一緒じゃなくない？
Eh, wait a second, isn't it different?
え、ペコら、ユニコーンって言ったじゃん。今、ユニコーンポーズじゃん。全然一緒にしてないからね。
Eh, Pekora, I said "unicorn"! This is the unicorn pose right now. You totally didn't do the same thing!
え、すごいめぐや、めぐや、びっくりした、めぐや。もう1個、もう1個決まってる、ルシアもう決まってたんだけど。
Eh, amazing, Megu-ya—wait, Megu-ya, I was surprised! Another one, another one is decided, Rushia already had another one decided though.
もう1個ね、もう1個、えっと。
Another one, another one, um...
待って。うん、あれにして。オッケー、決めた。
Wait. Yeah, let's go with that. Okay, decided.
これで見せたら可愛いペコじゃない？これ、いくよ。
If we show this, aren't we cute Peko? Here we go.
うん。せーの！
Yeah. Ready, set!
はい！
Go!
え、なんか違くない？
Eh, isn't it different?
やばいじゃん、あいつの次対決の対感、耐えられないんだけどだから！耐えられないから！
This is bad, the pressure of her next challenge is too much to bear, so—I can't bear it!
いや、待って、耐えられない、これちょっと、え、何にする？
No, wait, I can't bear it, this is a bit—eh, what should we do?
あ、ごめんごめんごめん。
Ah, sorry, sorry, sorry.
ペコらじゃ、アイドルたるもの片足立ちでずっとしなきゃいけないのに、
Pekora, as an idol, you have to stand on one leg the whole time,
ペコらたちきつかったよこれ、ちょっと。
but it was tough for us, you know, this.
そう、だからね、ラストで行く、ラストで。
That's right, so let's do it with the last one, the last one.
ラストのね、え、ラストをもう最大限の可愛いあれにしようかな。
The last one, um, let's make the last one the cutest possible pose!
やるわ、やるわ。
Let's do it, let's do it.
いや、もう決まんてんのか来世しようかな？
No, is it already decided? Shall we do it in our next life?
あれにしようかな。ねえ、勝ったな。
Shall we do that one? Hey, we won.
ね！
Right!
おい、そんな自信があるぺこなのかなよ。あ、勝ったわ。
Hey, are you really that confident, Peko? Ah, we won.
じゃあ、勝負ぺこで行くよ。おいいくよ。
Then, let's go with the battle, Peko! Hey, here we go!
せーの！
Ready, set!
はい！
Go!
おい、待て待て、一緒じゃない、お前ら一緒で、おい！
Hey, wait, wait, aren't we the same? You guys are the same, hey!
え、まって、一緒じゃない！
Eh, wait, it's not the same!
え、待って、うちらちょっと、えーと。
Eh, wait, us a bit, um...
え、でも、これは二人とも優秀ぺこじゃない？こう、お互いに可愛いじゃん。
Eh, but aren't we both exceptional, Peko? Like, we're both cute, right?
これ、ちょっともうなんか、どっちかとかなくて、両方アイドルで可愛いっていうことで。
This, let's just say neither is better, both are idols and cute, so—
この辺にしとくか、今日は。そうぺこ、だね、ぺこだね。
let's leave it at that for today. That's right, Peko, yeah, Peko, yeah.
じゃあじゃあじゃあじゃあ、ペコらペコら、次のサビ曲いきたいからさ、一緒にジャンプしない？
Then, then, then, Pekora, Pekora, since we want to go to the next chorus song, shouldn't we jump together?
よくあの、ジャンプした次のところにいるみたいな感じぺこ？
Like that feeling of being right where you jumped to?
そう！
Yes!
やろやろ！
Let's do it!
行くよ、ペコら基本ありがとう！ガチ基本ありがとうぺこ、オッケー！
Here we go, Pekora basic thanks! Serious basic thanks Peko, okay!
次の言葉で、せーの！
On the next cue, ready, set!
はい！
Go!
いいおしりじゃーん！
Nice butt!
いや、ちょっとぺこあと歌ってきたんだよね。
Well, I just sang with Pekora, you know.
歌ってきたぺこだよ！
We sang together, Peko!
そうなんだ、歌ったんだ、歌ったんだ。
Is that so? You sang, you sang.
そう、ファンタジーだからね、怒ることもできちゃう、怒るよ、怒るよ、ぷんぷんるしあだー！
That's right, since it's fantasy, I can even get angry! I'll get mad, I'll get mad, pun-pun Rushia!
そう、今日はこのあとね、5人でとある曲を歌いたくて、やってまいりました。
That's right, today after this, the five of us wanted to sing a certain song, so we came here.
なんだろなんだろう、集まってもらいました。
I wonder what it is, we had everyone gather.
わかった、あれでしょ、きらめきライダーとかかな？え、7段とか？7段ライダーとかかな？
I know, it's that, "Kirameki Rider" or something? Eh, "Nanadan"? "Nanadan Rider" or something?
あれあれ、5人の曲、わかる人！
Hey hey, the song for five people, whoever knows it!
あれ、うそじゃん。
Huh, no way.
ねえ、忘れないで、絆を。
Hey, don't forget our bond.
ここじゃないの？
Is this not it?
違う違う
No, no!
5人分とか…ねえ？
Like, for 5 people... right?
ねーっ
Yeah!
5人分だからさ
Because it's for 5 people.
インスタントリップもね、私達よく歌ったよね。
We used to sing Instant Trip a lot too.
歌った！
We did!
ほら！ほらほら！
Look! Look, look!
い…焼肉！
Y... Yakiniku!
焼肉いっちゃって！
Let's go eat yakiniku!
マリンさっき焼肉行ったもんね
Marine went to eat yakiniku earlier, didn't she?
ペコラいっちゃって！
Pekora, go ahead!
いっちゃっていいぺこ？じゃもう正解いっちゃうよ！いい？
Should I go ahead, peko? Then I'll give the correct answer! Is that okay?
うん、うん
Yeah, yeah.
いくよ！うん。
Here we go! Yeah.
ペコラガチでいっちゃうよ！いいの？ほんとに。
Pekora's gonna really say it! Is that okay? Really?
マジで？分かるかな？
Seriously? Do you know?
え、待って、他に5人で歌った曲ってなんかあったけな？
Eh, wait, were there any other songs the five of us sang?
まぁいいや！
Whatever!
せーの！いくよ！せーの！
Ready, set! Here we go! Ready, set!
なんだろう？いくよ、せーの！
What could it be? Here we go, ready!
なんだろう？
What is it?
うん。
Yeah.
なんか並んでから
Somehow, after lining up...
なんでからペコ、なんでから？な、うん、よ！
After what, peko, after what? Na, un, yo!
いきます！
Here we go!
インタラクとファンタジア！
Interact Fantasia!
そうワクワクは止まらないね インタラクとファンタジア！
No stopping this hype train, interact fantasia!
wake up fantasia!!
きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル
This is a never-ending fairy tale
wake up fantasia, let's go!! いえーい！
Wake up, fantasia, let's go! Yay!
ぺこら！
Pekora!
ドンドンどん！目指すは頂点だ！
Du-dun-dun-dun! Aim for the top!
ほらついてくるぺこ！
Follow my lead as we peko!
るしあ！
Rushia!
ちょっと、ちょっと待ってよ！みんなで一緒に！
Wait, wait! Let's all go together!
ねぇなんか頼りないなくない？
You know, I'm not so sure about this now
フレア！
Flare!
怖いもの無し進めいざファイト！
There's nothing to fear, keep going, keep fighting!
ノエル！
Noel!
たまには泣いちまってもマイペースに
It's okay to cry sometimes, take it as you go
マリン！
Marine!
あほい！さぁ手を取り合ったら
Ahoy! Once we take each other's hands
冒険の幕が開ける！
The curtain rises on our adventure!
たちまち通り過ぎて行く昨日をその目に焼き付け
As the days come and go, let's take all the sights in
広がる空も海も大地も重ねあった思い出を溢れさせ
The vast, open skies, the ocean and the land, and use those memories to fuel us
明日へと走り続けよう！
While we face each new day, chasing after our boundless dream
果てしない夢を追う真っ直ぐに
Chasing after our boundless dream
君となら怖くはないから
You are here with me and give me strength
戸惑いも全部その背中に預け合い
When we share the burden of all our fears and anxieties
道なき道も楽しみながら走れる！
We can enjoy going down this untrodden path
心が今を告げるさぁ行くよ
Our hearts give the signal, it's time to go
進むべき未来が待ってる
The future of our dreams is waiting for us
他でもない君がいるから
I couldn't do it without you, but here you are
繋げよう君と僕の世界
So let's bring our worlds together
ここから旅は始まっている
Our journey has already begun
wake up fantasia!!
きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル
This is a never-ending fairy tale
wake up fantasia, let's go!! いえーい！
Wake up, fantasia, let's go! Yay!
ノエフレ！
Noe-Fla!
hello! everlasting tale!
日常を照らし出すtwin quasar!
Our lives illuminated by twin quasars!
ペコマリるし！
Peko-Mari-Rushi!
退屈にbye-bye声上げstart!
Say goodbye to the doldrums, raise your voice, and start!
着いてこれるよね？twinkle dream!
We know you can keep up with this twinkle dream!
1！
One!
今駆け出す時は来た
It's time to set off
2！
Two!
心の準備はおっけー？
Are you ready for this? All okay?
3！
Three!
さぁ鐘を鳴らせば
Now ring the bell and start a new chapter!
伝説が一歩拓く！
The courage to take the first step will cast a magic spell
わずかに踏み出した勇気が魔法になるから
世界の果ても次元の壁も吹き飛ばして今君に会いに行こう
Beyond the ends of the earth, past the screens between us, we come to see you
一緒に飛び出してみない？
So why don't you take a leap of faith too?
届かない夢はないどこででも
No dream is unattainable, with you we can go as far as we want
君となら辿り着けるから
Your incessant cheering guides our hands
とめどないエールをその両手に握り締め
Your incessant cheering guides our hands to the paper
白紙の地図を描き回して駆け出そう！
As we chart every corner of this once-blank map and set off
願いと共に歌う聴こえるよ
Singing our prayers out loud, we can hear it
窓越しのファンタジーであっても
While it may be a fantasy playing out on the screen
出会いは幻じゃないから
Our connection is not an illusion
繋げよう君と僕の声
So let's bring our voices together with a miracle
奇跡を奏し合うシンフォニー
And break out in symphony forever and ever
いつまでも
Forever and ever
ちょっと強くないたくて
We wanted to be stronger
ずっと笑い合いたくて
We wanted to share all the laughter
色付く気持ち銀翼に結んで
So we sent out a message in 0s and 1s
君と出会えたよ
And finally found you
失敗も後悔もさせるわけないよ
There will be no dead ends or regrets
だって毎日楽しすぎでしょ
Every day is an adventure filled with wonder
トキメキの先の先へ
So we keep running as we are
裸足で駆け抜けろ！
To wherever our racing hearts take us
行こう！
Let's go!
果てしない夢を追う真っ直ぐに
Chasing after our boundless dream
君となら怖くはないから
You are here with me and give me strength
戸惑いも全部その背中に預け合い
When we share the burden of all our fears and anxieties
道なき道も楽しみながら走れる！
We can enjoy going down this untrodden path
心が今を告げるさぁ行くよ
Our hearts give the signal, it's time to go
進むべき未来が待ってる
The future of our dreams is waiting for us
他でもない君がいるから
I couldn't do it without you, but here you are
繋げよう君と僕の世界
So let's bring our worlds together
いつまでも旅は終わらない
This journey will never end
wake up fantasia!! (it's my fantasia)
きっとここが消えないフェアリーテイル
This is a never-ending fairy tale
wake up fantasia, let's go!! いえーい！
Wake up, fantasia, let's go! Yay!
まえふれ！
Illuminate our daily lives
煩わして日常を照らし出すスワインクエスタ
Say goodbye to boredom
退屈にバイバイ声上げスタン
Now is the time to start running
今駆け出す時は来た
Are you ready?
心の準備はおっけー？
Ring the bell
鈴の音を鳴らせば
A legend begins
伝説が一歩拓く
The courage you take becomes magic
わずかに踏み出した勇気が魔法になるから
Blow away the ends of the world and dimensions
世界の果ても次元の壁も吹き飛ばして今君に会いに行こう
Why don't we jump out together?
一緒に飛び出してみない？
There are no unreachable dreams
届かない夢はない
Forever and ever
ちょっと強くなりたくて
We wanted to be stronger
ずっと笑い合いたくて
We wanted to share all the laughter
色付く気持ち銀翼に結んで
So we sent out a message in 0s and 1s
君と出会えたよ
And finally found you
失敗も後悔もさせるわけないよ
There will be no dead ends or regrets
だって毎日楽しすぎでしょ
Every day is an adventure filled with wonder
ときめきの先の先へ
So we keep running as we are
裸足で駆け抜けろ！
To wherever our racing hearts take us
行こう！
Let's go!
果てしない夢を追う真っ直ぐに
Chasing after our boundless dream
だんだん ココロ だんだん アツク
Dan-dan, my heart is getting warmer
夢いっぱい 叶えてみせる
We'll make all of our dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Dan-dan, stepping forward, dan-dan, bursting with energy
未来をしっかり見て！
Keep your eyes on the future!
（Hi hi, ススメ！ まだまだLet's go!!）
(Hi, hi! Let's go! Still plenty of time, let's go!)
（Hi hi, ススメ！ ほらほらLet's go!!）
(Hi, hi! Look over there, let's go!)
大切なことはなんだっけ？
What was the most important thing again?
ちいさな努力が明日を作るんだ
A little effort makes tomorrow
いまを愛してぶつかろう！
Let's embrace the present and collide!
そんな勢いでずっと一生懸命なんだって
With that kind of momentum, always giving it our all
（一生懸命なんだってばっ！）
(Always giving it our all!)
もっと近くで語り合いたいな
I want to talk and share more closely
寄り添う君とどこまで走ろうか
How far shall we run together, with you nodding along?
（果てまで）走ればいいさ（限界しらない All right?）
(To the very end!) Just run if you want (No limits, all right?)
これからの Wonderful Rush
From now on, it's a wonderful rush
みんな幸せになるため
So that everyone can find happiness
新しい世界 探しに行こうよ
Let's go search for a new world!
迷ったら Wonderful Rush
If you ever hesitate during this wonderful rush
僕は輝きを信じて
I believe in that brilliance
遥か遠くの虹だけど…そう、きっとつかんで！（Hi!!）
Even though the rainbow is far away... yes, I'll definitely grasp it! (Hi!!)
イェーイ！
Yay!
ひとりひとっ と、ほっこりしたのわかったでしょ？
You could tell how cozy we all were, right?
さすが、あたりまえペコだよ！
Naturally, that's just common sense, Peko!
あ、た、こ、や、た、ぽ、よ？
Wait, Atapoyo?
ライブいらってことだったね。
Meaning you came to the live!
ねえ、楽しかった！また歌える時が来るとは思わなんだ。うん。
Hey, it was so fun! I never thought the time to sing again would come... Yeah.
確かに。
True.
ねー！ところでさ、みんな、もう今年も入ったけど、
Hey! By the way, everyone, we're already into this year, but
だね。2022年、みんなのさ、目標を聞いてもいいかな？
That's right. In 2022, can we hear everyone's goals?
目標ね。うん、北極もね、いいよ。うん、北極も。
Goals? Yeah, the North Pole is fine too. Yeah, the North Pole.
これはね、みんなのっていうか、自分の…みんなの、先にるしあからよっかな？
Wait, not everyone's, but your own... Wait, should we start with Rushia first?
はい！潤羽るしあ！
Yes! Uruha Rushia!
三期生のみんなと、地上波に出たいです！
I want to appear on terrestrial television with everyone in the 3rd generation!
おおー！でっかく出ました！
Ooh! That's going big!
あれ、まだ5人に出てない、ぺこだもん。そうか。じゃあ次ね、ノエル！
Wait, we haven't appeared as 5 people yet, Peko. That's right. So next, Noel!
はい！私は、え、どうしようかな？
Yes! As for me, um, what should I do?
え、なんかさ、三期生のみんなでお揃いのものとかをちょっと付けたりとか、
Um, like, having matching items for everyone in the 3rd generation, or wearing them together,
あ、いい！でっかいなと思って。
Ah, I thought it's great! It's pretty big.
女の子だね、かわいいね。お揃いしたい、お揃い、いいね。
So girly, cute. I want matching ones, matching is nice.
好きだよね、ノエルね、お揃いとかくれるもんね、なんか。
You like that kind of stuff, Noel, you always give us matching things.
お土産って言って。
Calling them souvenirs.
探してみると下がっちゃうじゃん。あ、これ水色だからペコらだとかさ。
When you look for them, the price drops. Ah, this is light blue so it's Pekora's, etc.
かわいいよね。ありがとね、いつもね。まだぬいぐるみ大事にしてんだよ。
It's cute. Thanks as always. I still cherish the plushie, you know.
じゃ、次、ぺこちゃん！
Well then, next, Pekora-chan!
はい！ペコーラは、そうだな、これはたぶん大人の人たちの協力がないとできないのかもしれないぺこですが、
Yes! Pekoras, well, this might not be possible without the cooperation of adults, Peko, but
ホロライブファンタジー、三期生のギャルゲを誰か作ってください！
Please, someone make a visual novel game for Hololive Fantasy, the 3rd generation!
ギャルゲ！？ギャルゲーかー。意外と意外とね、めっちゃいいじゃん。
A visual novel?! A visual novel. Surprisingly, that's actually really good.
いや、ギャルゲーじゃなくてもいいぺこなだけど、なんか三期生でのゲームとかそういうのとか、なんか欲しいなって、今年は思ったペコから。
Well, it doesn't have to be a visual novel, Peko, but I thought this year I'd want a game or something featuring the 3rd generation.
語りかけるほうがいいかもだけどね。
Talking directly might be better though.
語りかけ、語りかけ、いいね、してほしいな、いいな、めっちゃいいじゃん。
Direct talk, direct talk, nice, I want you to do it, that's great, really good.
え、じゃちょっと、ゲームもお願いします！お願いします！
Uh, then please make a game too! Please! We request it!
え、次、マリン！
Next, Marine!
え、そうだな、じゃあ、地上波っていうのが出たから、地上波は地上波でもアニメ、アニメにしましょう！アニメいいよね！
Um, well, since "terrestrial TV" came up, whether it's terrestrial or not, let's make it an anime! Anime is great!
アニメってすごいね！万が一、地上波のテレビに出たらどうせ滑り散らかすんで、やめろ、やめろ、やめて、やめて！
Anime is amazing! If we somehow appeared on terrestrial TV, we'd definitely make a fool of ourselves, so stop, stop, stop, stop!
アニメ化で行きましょう！じゃあ、アニメにしたいな、キャラクターに。
Let's go with an anime adaptation! Well, I want to turn it into an anime, into characters.
なんか、こうやってたいね！アフレコしなきゃね、アフレコね、しなきゃね、頑張らなきゃね。
I want to do this! We'd have to do voice acting, voice acting, we gotta try our best.
じゃ、次、フレア！
Well then, next, Flare!
そうだな、なんかやっぱ、地上波は出たいなって思うんだけど、私たちに一番合ってるやつ、そうだな、M1とか？
Let's see, I do want to appear on terrestrial TV, but the one that fits us best... yeah, maybe M-1 (comedy contest)?
お笑い、なんでだよ！みんなで一緒にでようよ！M-1で！
Comedy?! Why?! Let's all enter together! On M-1!
誰がネタ拾うんだよ。みんなでいろんなジャンル出たいねってことで、
Who's going to write the material? That means we want to appear in all sorts of genres together.
いろんなのが集まりました。で、みんながそう一致してるのは、やっぱりこうテレビとかゲームとかだったね。
Various things came together. And what everyone agreed on was TV and games.
やりたいね！絶対やりたいね！今年カナエよ！叶えよう！やんぞ！
We want to do it! We definitely want to do it! Let's make it happen this year! Let's do it!
みんなこっちもよろしくね！よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please take care of this side too! Thank you very much!
撮ろっか
Let's take a photo.
あっ、いいね！
Ah, nice!
どんな感じ？
What kind of feel?
ソロか？
Solo?
記念写真だ
It's a commemorative photo.
一緒に、一緒にしよう
Let's do it together.
どうなんだろ、ねえちょっとみんなでさ
Wonder how it is, hey, everyone together...
あ、縮こまるか？
Ah, crouch down?
可愛いね、みんな
Everyone is so cute.
ルーちゃま真ん中にさ、ルーちゃま真ん中
Ru-chama in the middle, Ru-chama in the middle.
えー、ありがとう
Um, thank you.
ルーちゃま、ここね
Ru-chama, right here.
お誕生日と
And your birthday.
えっ、ジャマなんですけど
Eh, you're in the way though.
嬉しいんだけど
I'm happy though.
うれしい、うれしい
Happy, happy.
あ、じゃあ、こんな感じでいいか？
Ah, then, is this kind of feel okay?
みんな、ルーちゃまの頭、まりが隠れちゃってる
Everyone, Ru-chama's head, Mari's hidden.
いえーい！
Yay!
どう、どう？いっぱいいい？
How is it? Is a lot okay?
やってくれ
Do it.
お客さんのほう反対側向いてもよくない？
Wouldn't it be good if the audience turned the other way?
あ、いいね、そこから回るの？
Ah, nice, going around from there?
いける？
Can you?
なんかよくライブでやるやつだよ
That's something they often do at lives.
ええぞ！ええぞ！ええぞ！
Great! Great! Great!
すごい！
Amazing!
しゃがんでさ
Squatting down...
ととろとろ
Totorotoro.
しゃがんでね
Squat down.
じゃあ、ルーちゃま、ちょっとぶるんこするわ
Then, Ru-chama, I'll do a little burunko.
ぶるんこ？しおかのぶるんこ？
Burunko? Shioka's burunko?
私も
Me too.
私もぶるんこってどうしたらいいの？
What should I do for burunko too?
ぶるんこ...
Burunko...
あ、ごめんなさい、こうして
Ah, sorry, like this.
ふり、ふり？
Swing, swing?
かがんだほうがいいのかな
Maybe it's better to crouch down.
かがんだほうがいいかも
Yeah, maybe crouching is better.
お前のスカート、しゃがんだら、こうか
Your skirt, when crouching, like this?
こうか、こうか、こうか？
Like this, like this, like this?
あ、いいね、いいね、いいね
Ah, nice, nice, nice.
あ、いいの？
Ah, is it good?
立って、たくさん飛び跳ねて
Stand up and jump around a lot.
こんな感じかな
Something like this?
カメラもっと上、上、上、上から...
Camera more up, up, up, from above...
いいね、いいね、そうそうそうそう
Nice, right, exactly.
ここにサインを入れたいね、みんなの
I want to put signatures here, everyone's.
あ、入れたいね
Ah, I want to put them.
みんなで無いじゃん
Everyone doesn't have it.
撮れた？撮れた？
Did it get taken? Taken?
これじゃだめなの？
Is this no good?
え、可愛い
Eh, cute.
ってことでね
So that's it.
時間も迫ってきたんで、みんな
Time is getting close, everyone.
今日は、ありがとう本当に！
Today, thank you so much!
ありがとう、本当に！
Thank you so much!
ありがとうね、ありがとうね
Thank you, thank you.
今年もどうかみんなで仲良く過ごしましょう
Let's all get along and spend this year well too.
じゃあみんな、また遊ぼう！
Well everyone, let's play again!
オッケー！
Okay!
バイバーイ！お疲れ様！またねー！
Bye-bye! Good work! See you!
私はいつも臆病で
I've always been so timid,
何をするにも怖くて
Scared to do anything at all,
すぐ諦めちゃうんだ
I'd give up right away.
自信なんて全然なくて
I had absolutely no confidence,
人の背中ばかり見ていた
Always looking at other people's backs.
それでいいと思ってた
I thought that was fine.
だけど振り返ったあなたが笑ってくれたことを
But when I looked back and remembered you smiling at me,
何を話したのかも覚えていないけれど散らばる言葉は春の匂いがした
I don't even remember what we talked about, but the scattered words smelled like spring.
これが恋なんだって初めて気づいたんだよ
I realized for the first time that this is love.
出会えたことが話せたことがこんなに嬉しくって確かめたいんだ溢れ出すこの想いを
Meeting you, being able to talk to you, makes me so happy—I want to make sure of these overflowing feelings.
もっと近くで伝えられたらいいのに
If only I could convey them to you closer,
だけど今の私ではだめなんだ
But for the me right now, it's no good.
私はいつも不器用でうまく言葉が出なくて
I'm always clumsy and can't find the right words,
思っていることが綺麗に伝わればいいのに
I wish what I'm thinking could be conveyed clearly.
あなたのことばかり見ていた偶然を期待してはもしかしたらなんて思い描いたりして
I was always looking only at you, hoping for a coincidence, and imagining "what if?"
だけどふとした時に思えがけず気づいたんだ
But I suddenly realized unexpectedly
あなたの視線のさらにいる人のこと
About the person further along your line of sight.
こんなにいたいんだって初めて想い知るんだ
I realize for the first time how much it hurts.
今のままでも幸せだって思ってたはずなのに
Even though I thought I'd be happy just as I am,
止まることのない想いは涙に変わり心配なんてしてほしいわけじゃないのに
My unstopping feelings turn into tears—not that I want you to worry,
でもね、やっぱり少しだけされたいな
But still, I want you to notice me just a little bit.
夜は気になるとどうせ私なんてなくていつも諦めてたけど
At night, when I get curious, thinking "it's no use for someone like me anyway," I'd always give up, but...
痛くても 辛くても
Even if it hurts, even if it's painful,
私が見つけた 私だけの
the feeling I found all by myself,
この気持ちは 話したくないよ
I don't want to let go of it.
話したくないよ
I don't want to let go.
これが恋なんだって 初めて気づいたんだよ
I realized for the first time that this is love.
風に揺られて どこを向いても あなたへと伸びてくんだ
Swaying in the wind, wherever I look, it reaches out to you.
誰よりもきっと あなたのことが好きだよ
I surely love you more than anyone else.
もっと近くで この気持ち伝えたいの
I want to convey these feelings to you closer by.
だから こんな私では
That's why someone like me...
みんな お誕生日配信来てくれて本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday stream!
どうだったかな？るしあは今日本当に素敵な一日になれたよ。
How was it? Rushia had a truly wonderful day today.
お誕生日配信見に来てくれて本当に本当にありがとう！
Thank you so, so much for coming to see my birthday stream!
そして お誕生日記念として販売するグッズの案内をするね。
And now, I'd like to introduce the merchandise for my birthday!
それではまず 1点目はこちら！
First up is this item!
やすゆき先生描き下ろしの 花嫁るしあアクリルスタンド！
Yasuyuki-sensei's illustrated Bride Rushia Acrylic Stand!
みてみて！すっごくかわいくない？
Look, look! Isn't it super cute?
めちゃくちゃ綺麗じゃない？
Isn't it insanely gorgeous?
お、これはね、るしあみんなのお嫁さんになります！
Oh, this means Rushia will become everyone's bride!
もうお部屋とかね、パソコンデスクの周りとか、君の近くに すぐそばに置いといてください。
Please put it right near you, in your room or around your PC desk.
るしあがずっと見てるからね。
'Cause Rushia will be watching you all the time.
そして 2点目は るしあと一生一緒エンゲージリングです！
And the second item is the "Engaged to Rushia Forever" ring!
これは、これは 結婚指輪ってやつではないですか？
Isn't it... isn't this like a wedding ring?
どうですか？ これは君たちと一緒に つける指輪です。
What do you think? This is a ring to wear together with you guys.
いや、ちょっとドキドキしちゃうね。とっても綺麗で可愛くない？
Man, it makes my heart race. Isn't it super pretty and cute?
もう 生涯に一度の代物ですよ。
It's a once-in-a-lifetime treasure.
いや、これはみんなと一緒に ぜひぜひぜひ付けたい！るしあ毎日これを付けて配信します。
I really, really, really want us all to wear this together! I'll stream wearing this every day.
そして 最後の 3点目は こちら！
And the final third item is this!
沙高先生描き下ろしの ペアマグカップセットになります！
It's a pair mug cup set illustrated by Sakou-sensei!
いや、ペアだらけだね。ペアだらけだね。
Man, it's full of pairs! Full of pairs!
見てこのマグカップ。朝起きた時とか、寝る前とか、休憩とかも ずっと一緒なんだよ。
Look at these mugs. When you wake up, before bed, during breaks, we'll always be together.
可愛いでしょう？これはね、るしあバージョンとファンレッドちゃんバージョンのコップになります。
Cute, right? These are mugs in a Rushia version and a Fanred-chan version.
いや、みんなと使いたいな。君とのお揃いいっぱいになったね。
I want to use them with everyone. We've got so many matching things now.
これもね、配信しながらるしあ使って飲んでるから、君たちもるしあの配信見ながらこれを使って飲めば、もうるしあたち 結婚生活だね！
I use this while streaming too, so if you guys drink from it while watching my stream, it's practically married life for us!
はい、もうこんなにね、素敵なグッズたくさん盛りだくさんどうですか？
So, how do you like having so many wonderful goods packed together?
そして なんとなんとなんと！お誕生日記念フルセットは 今紹介したグッズにるしあの複製サイン入りポストカードがついてきます！
And what's more, the birthday full set comes with a postcard featuring Rushia's duplicated signature!
ででででで！数量限定バージョンのものには、るしあの直筆メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます！
And, and, and! The quantity-limited version comes with a postcard featuring Rushia's handwritten message!
直筆ですよ、直筆！どどどどど、よちきですよ、よちき！
Handwritten, literally handwritten! Yochiki, yochiki!
周年記念のサインも書き終わってるので、改めてみんなのために愛情をこくこくこめたメッセージを書いていきます。
I've already finished signing for the anniversary too, so I'll be writing messages filled with deep affection for you all.
よかったらみんな どんどん感想ツイートなどなどしていってね。
If you'd like, please feel free to tweet your thoughts and impressions.
そして まだ！実話ここは終わりでなくて、もう少し見てもらいたいものがあります。
And wait! Actually, it doesn't end here, there's something else I want you to see.
行きます。てでん！
Here we go. Ta-da!
みんな！ 今日は本当に本当に 生誕祭ライブ...
Everyone! Today's birthday live was truly, truly...
見に来てくれて本当にありがとうね！
Thank you so much for coming to watch!
おっおっ？
Oh? Oh?
何か気づいたことある？
Did you notice anything?
この猫耳とツインテールとチョーカー、じゃーん！
These cat ears, twin tails, and choker... Tada!
これは、実は、るしあの誕生日だからといって、やすゆきお父様が、るしあにプレゼントして下さいました！
Actually, since it's Rushia's birthday today, Yasuyuki-papa kindly gifted these to me!
へへへへ。
Hehehe...
かわいいね？似合ってんね？ふふっ。
Cute, right? Suits me, right? Hehe.
ってことでこの姿でも配信をしていくので、みんなこれからも仲良く、るしあと遊んでいってください。
So, I'll be streaming in this look too, so please keep getting along and playing with Rushia.
そして、グッズなんですけど、10時から、えー発売されるので、概要欄から飛んでいって、どんどんグッズを手に取ってみてください。
And as for the merch, it goes on sale at 10:00, so please check the description and grab some!
サイン入り幼チェキですよ！
They're signed baby Chekis!
他にもね、素敵な指輪など、えーマグカップなどたくさんあるので、みんなよかったらたくさん、えーそばに置いてみてください。
There are also wonderful rings, mugs, and lots of other things, so please keep them close by if you'd like.
本当に本当に今日は素敵な1日をありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for such a wonderful day today.
みんな大好きだよ！本当にありがとう！
I love you all so much! Thank you so much!
みんな、せーの、おつるしー！ありがとう！
Everyone, ready, set—Otsurushi! Thank you!